Tiago Fonseca da Silva

Full Stack Developer, Social Innovator and Activist

+351 917830996

contact@tiagoseixas.com







Being in love by sustainability, diversity and social innovation but I always had a crush on technology and special ways to implement ideas. I've worked as Social Engineer, and than I decided to create my own Sustainability Consultant firm, being self-taught myself most of time I developed, front-end web, leadership, management, creative thinking, and fast problem-solving skills. I'm now a full stack developer, and it has been quite a ride and I found a new passion in software programming.

PROJECTS

Full-Stack Developer

Open Source

- Noa Intranet Virtual Assistance React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoSB
- Populis Electronic Vote Prototype NodeJS, ExpressJS, Handlebars, MongoSB
- Ironhacking Shooting Inclusive Game Javascript, CSS, HTML

Institucional

Front-End HTML, CSS, PHP JS, WP, Cloudflare, AWS, Google Seo

- Institutional Website CORE CRL
- Platform Crowdfunding Quebr'a Corrente
- Platform Observatório da Responsabilidade Social
- Directory de Responsabilidade Social
- Website institutional CES-Fonte Boa

WORK EXPERIENCES

Startup Founder and Front-End Developer

CORE | 2014 - Present

As a startup founder I development and implement skills to let CORE reach and communicate efficiency with clients, thought multiple websites implementation, seo strategies. I also worked as team leader focusing to accomplish client needs on time, engaging the rest of the team.

Sustainability, Corporate Responsibility Consultant and trainer

I develop new skills targeting social and environment themes, to help companies achieve accountable high levels of sustainability standards with shared value creation. Main Clients: Galp, AKI, BPI, SIBS, Introsys

2013 - Present

Secretary General & South Europe Region Director

Worked mainly to propose and brainstorm ideas to send to UN regarding macro community developing policies

UK - IACD | 2010 - 2013

Assistant Team Leader - Housing First Program

Worked on the implementation and research of a disruptive, bold housing US project targeting 50 homeless with mental disorders in Lisbon

AEIPS | 2009 - 2012

Professor & Research Assistant

Work as university teacher on community psychology bachelor program

ISPA-IU | 2008 - 2012

SKILLS

Technical

JavaScript/React

Node.js/Express/Mongo

HTML/CSS/Wordpress

Docker/Proxmox/Kubernetes /KVM

Cloudflare/Pfsense

Linux/Bash/Apache/Git/Nginx



Professional

Leadership | Fast Problem-Solving Creative Thinking | Management Team Leader

EDUCATION

Full-Stack BootCamp

Ironhack Lisbon 2021 - 2021

MSc in Community Psychology

ISPA University 2013-2015

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (Native) | English (Professional) Spanish (Professional) | Italian (Conversation)

INTERESTS

Fencing | Surfing | Podcasting && Travel

